# **Ethan Holen**

#### COLORADO STATE UNIVERSITY CLASS OF 2022, B.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE

□ 720-326-5046 | ■ ethanholen@gmail.com | # ethanholen.com | □ EthanHolen | □ ethan-holen-563856174

#### Summarv 5 4 1

Current IOS Developer, and undergraduate at Colorado State University with experience in both the software and hardware side of the tech industry as well as the medical field. Super nerd who loves Vim, Linux and OS X and enjoys backpacking, mountain biking and camping in the mountains of Colorado. Interested in gaining new and interesting experiences in the field of Computer Science.

# Work Experience

**IOS Development** 

Denver CO

IOS Developer July. 2019 - Present

- Currently working with Mayo clinic to design a custom vaccine App for patient care
- Designed using SwiftUI

IOS Development Denver CO

IOS Developer May. 2019 - Present

- Wrote custom IOS Application for Douglas County Sheriffs Office
- Designed and Created a secure back-end using AWS Lambda and API Gateway
- Collaborated with non technical individuals to determine development goals

#### **Valor Christian High School**

Highlands Ranch, CO.

IT Intern Aug. 2016 - May. 2018

- Provided hardware and software solutions for help desk tickets
- Helped manage a JAMF environment of 550 Apple devices
- Setup and management of 20 Aerohive network access points

Express Care Cheyenne, WY

MEDICAL ASSISTANT May. 2016 - Jul. 2016

- Assisted Doctor or PA on call as a scribe
- · Vitals and initial patient charts
- · Strep, urine and vision tests

# **Education**

## COLORADO STATE UNIVERSITY(COLLEGE OF NATURAL SCIENCES)

Fort Collins, CO

**B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE** 

Jan. 2019 - PRESENT

• Relevant Coursework: Intro to Java Programming (Java), Data Structures (Java)

#### SAINT LOUIS UNIVERSITY(COLLEGE OF ARTS AND SCIENCES)

Saint Louis, MO

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, PRE MED

• Relevant Coursework: Managing Big Data (Python)

Aug. 2018 - Dec. 2018

# Valor Christian High School

Highlands Ranch, CO

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA

Aug. 2014 - May. 2018

• Relevant Coursework: AP Computer Science (Java)

# Extracurricular Activity \_

#### **Skills & Talents**

PERSONAL

- Programming Languages: Java, Python, HTML, CSS, Bash, Swift
- Software: OSX, Windows, Linux, AWS, Xcode, Personal Website
- · Hardware: Custom PC, Mac Repairs, Raspberry Pi

#### **Eagle Scout - Troop 102**

Greenwood Village, CO

Sep. 2011 - May. 2015

PATROL LEADER, TROOP HISTORIAN

· Learned Leadership and organization through positions of patrol leader and troop historian

Project: Build garden and fence around local monastery

Medical Missions Work Ethiopia

MEDICAL ASSISTANT Aug. 2017

- Assisted physicians with scribe work and basic medical tests.
- Video: https://govalor.com/discovery-ethiopia-video/